# **Ahmet OZKESEK**

M: 0772 922 3112 E: <u>aozkesek@gmail.com</u>

### Summary

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I mostly worked for Contact Centre, ATM Management, Document Management and Work-Flow Management in Banking and Financial sector for 16 years in Istanbul-Turkey. Since 2017 I chose voluntarily being unemployed to focus on myself and study again to improve my skills. Now I am looking a mid-level Java programmer role while I am enjoying being a state pensioner in my home country.

# **Experience**

Oct 2016 - date	Istanbul, London	Freelancer

- Passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-ocp.pdf
- Passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (94%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-oca.pdf
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 from Nigeria. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm">https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm</a> <a href="https://ziezix360.com/about-us/">https://ziezix360.com/about-us/</a>
- Developed a group of PoC applications for an e-commerce web site and it's test automations <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce">https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce</a> <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner">https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner</a>

Jul 2014 - Aug 2016	NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant
na Lori rag Loro	1121713, 131411341	Compareame

- Designed some services and wrote their Technical Design Document for companies that use Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program
   https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program\_benefits/overvi

https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program\_benefits/overview/index.gsp

https://downloads.avaya.com/css/P8/documents/101026461

- Developed a web application for managing a group of Cisco IP Phone Services <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager">https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager</a>
- Trained the junior team members

Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	10.01.10.00.	C C

• Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months

- Developed and maintained Workflow and Document Management software
- Developed and maintained ATM and Telephone Banking softwares
- Involved merging of Unicredit Kocbank and Yapi Kredi Bank
- Developed and maintained On-line and Telephone Banking software

Aug 1999 - Aug 2001 Demirbank, Istanbul	Programmer
---	------------

Developed and maintained Telephone Banking and Contact Centre software

#### Skills

- Still developing skills:
  - AWS (IAM, ...),
  - Document DB / NoSQL (Mongo, Redis, Cassandra)
- Java 8, JavaScript
- C. C#
- TDD: Junit, TestNG, Selenium
- Containerization: Docker & Docker Compose, Podman
- SCM & Build & CI/CD: Git, Gradle, Maven, Make, Jenkins
- JEE: Spring Framework & Boot, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces
- ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- RDBMS: Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- JTAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

#### Education

University of Istanbul, 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (<a href="https://bilgisayarmuhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr/en/">https://bilgisayarmuhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr/en/</a>)

# **Qualifications**

- Pearson Vue, London, 2020: **OCP** Java 8 SE Programmer II, (1Z0-809, 81%) <a href="https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8">https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8</a>
- Pearson Vue, London, 2019: OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (1Z0-808, 94%)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: Certified GVP (IP IVR) Developer Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: CUCM Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: JSP, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified CTI Developer Course
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: ASP VBScript, COM VB & C++ Course